Thanks for watching AM Northwest. If
you're planning to have a garage sale soon,
our first guest has tips to make it a
winner. We welcome back antique appraiser
Gary Germer.
It's weird seeing you here
sitting on the [laughter] couch.
>> See the full the full scene here. >>
I love it. Okay, so you know how to host
a garage sale. We did this segment a
couple years ago, but things have changed
because of AI, but let's start with
set it up to look like a Nordstrom,
like or to look like a high-end store.
>> This is something that I I believe in
is that if you don't make your stuff
look good, why would anybody give you any
money for it? So, if you want to do well,
set it up, put like things together,
all the kitchen stuff here, all the toys
there, all the books here, so that it's
easily shopped. You keep it fluffed up
as things sell. >> I like that. >> And
you also the room, if it's in your garage
and your garage smells like a wet dog,
well, >> [snorts] >> you put some
freshener around, maybe have a potpourri
because smells sell, have a little bit
of music playing. >> the music sound.
>> Because people don't don't like the
echo. So, it's all about it's all about
making it as easy as possible for people
and make them want it, make it look
enticing. >> let's back up. We should
have started with uh how you advertise.
>> Okay. >> So, that's step one. You want
to advertise for it, right? >> There's
there's no real order, but yeah, we
can market it. And how you marketing,
there's two things you do. And one is is
is people worry about running the ads.
There's Craigslist, Nextdoor, things
like that that are free. So, if you're
expecting I'm going to raise a couple
hundred bucks and just clear out a few
closets, that's what you do. >> Okay.
>> If you're dealing with a whole house
full and you're hoping that you and
the neighbors have teamed up and you're
going to do a few thousand dollars, you
think, then it's worth paying for an ad
and you want to put it on like
a place like EstateSales.net
or EstateSales.org.
It costs you 25 to 50 dollars and you can
put pictures up to tease the people as
to what you have and you'll draw in a
bigger crowd. And I would say and 20% or
so of the people who come to your sale,
they're buyers, but they're the ones who
come from your the ad. The rest are
going to be in the neighborhood. >> Okay.
>> So, you want good signage. That's
Concentrate on really good signage. And I
have a thing where you want it to be
bold, easy to read, that they can see it
two blocks away if they're driving 30
miles an hour down the street, so they
have time to make a change. We do
>> Yeah. >> We do this. I Ours do
We have I have actually professional
people who work for me. I colored this one
myself and I and I failed
[laughter] Flint Art School.
>> Hey, that's what mine would look like.
So, you know. >> But But the biggest
thing is is that one word, "Sale",
"Estate Sale", and an arrow. There's no
confusion. And these would be ones that
you'd put like on a telephone pole to
direct them in. So, like here, we're
off Sandy Boulevard, you'd put your big
signs. You want to go get a poster board.
And and it can say "Estate Sale" or
some little thing. Don't put your life
story on it. Just there and an arrow. And
then these will drive you on exactly
where you need to be. >> sure it's black
ink because I've seen signs with
orange ink. And you know, the older
you get, the harder it is to see maybe,
but I had a hard time seeing the orange
on white. So, black ink, no matter
what. >> Black ink, yep. And you can use
fluorescent I Do not be subtle with your
signs. >> be subtle. [laughter] I love
that. Okay, so great signs, advertise,
and pay for an ad if it's going to be a
big one. >> If it's going to be [clears
throat] a big one, so go ahead and pay
for an ad. >> Okay. And then how do you
know how to price the things in your
garage sale? I was at a garage sale at
a big community where I grew up, and
there were some things for 25 cents.
I thought I'd gone back in time. I was
like, "Oh my god." I felt so bad buying
something for 25 cents. >> It doesn't
seem worth it. I won't put anything out
that's at least 50 cents, and there's a
reason for that is that first of all, if
it isn't worth 50 cents, throw it in a
free box, you know. >> Yeah, yeah. >>
Keep moving, but I suggest before you
start pricing, go to Goodwill. >> Okay.
>> And and do some homework. What are
they asking for books? What are they
asking You'll be shocked. I'm shocked on
used clothing what people pay for used
clothing that's in good condition.
>> Yeah. >> And books and so you can
do homework, pots and pans and all your
household stuff. And if you stay close
to Goodwill pricing or maybe just
slightly below Goodwill pricing, that
will be fine. Uh and you should do fine on
that. I say 50% or more because then you
can say hey that's all half off at the
very end and and I can divide 50
better than I can 25. >> 25, exactly.
[laughter]
I like it cuz I feel like inflation
like 50 cents is still a good deal for
anything really. >> a cup of coffee is
what? Four, five bucks now and a pizza's
almost 30. >> Yeah. >> The other way
people are using is AI and I kind of want
to give a little bit of a of a warning
on that is that um it's coming along
really well and probably in 2 years
I'll be fired, but um >> [laughter]
>> You're fired from your own business.
>> Uh but they're still running about
an 80% accuracy, but if you have nice
things that can kind of direct you as
to what you have and then but always
double-check it and double-check the
pricing on it. >> Like you ask AI if I were
selling this at a garage sale, what would
I charge for this? >> Well, Chat GPT
and uh Google Lens are probably the two
I use happen to use the most. There's
others out there. They have photo
picture you can shoot a picture of it and
it'll here's what you have. >> Okay.
>> But I've had it where it's done it I
knew what it was and they'll say oh
that's a necklace from Bali you know from
the 1930s and give you a whole long story
Chat GPT especially and then I'll say
no it's not. I know that it's Navajo
you know and I'll tell it correct it and
then it goes oh you're absolutely
right you're such a genius you know.
[laughter]
>> Oh it's so patronizing. >> So you
really have to you use it but it's a tool.
It's not it's not the Bible. >> Okay.
>> You know. >> Okay. And And I would
guess that that's just for things that
you think could be valuable and you want
to make sure you don't sell if it is
valuable cuz then that would go somewhere
else. >> Right. And don't put out gold
or silver speaking of valuables. So tell
me why. Well, it's all downside and no
upside. You can sell it after the fact in
other places and get your money
without the risk of being robbed or or
shoplifted. >> Oh. >> And so it's just
something that it's a all security and no
one wants to pay over melt for anything
anyway at the garage sale. >> Okay. Oh,
we're running out of time. So I'm trying
to think Okay, so have change, we know
that. What do you recommend?
>> What on James >> and change like $50
and change? >> 50 I mean 50 is not the
bigger thing is do not take $100 bills
or $50 bills. >> Okay. >> There's a bunch
of them floating around and we've managed
through our estate sales to get both.
So I you know, that that are fake. So
you want do just don't take them anymore.
And make people give you a lower bills.
Um >> Interesting. >> And then don't
barter until the very last day of your
sale. >> Good. >> First day dig your
heels in. You should have a right to
get the price that you think it's worth.
And then barter at the end, you know. >>
back the last hour of the second day if
you want it. >> Right. And then if it's
a big heavy horrible thing, at the very
end put it out for free. Free is as Tom
Peterson used to say free is a very good
price. >> Yes, it is. >> You know, and
so >> And then don't ever let anyone
inside your house. >> Yeah, that just
very common sense security. Don't let them
in. You know, and >> And always have
two people minimum running the show.
>> Right. Somebody watching the money
while the other one is selling the stuff.
>> Right. And the final tip, I like
this one from last time. You said give a
blessing to everything that sells. Don't
worry about if you sold something too
cheap. Just let it go. >> Yep. Absolutely.
Just let it go. It's a joy just to
see the empty garage. >> Exactly. Okay,
[laughter] great tips. Thanks, Gary.
>> Thank you. >> Okay, we'll be right
back with more AM Northwest. Stay with us.
Good.